Parker-Gray Historic District Papers, 1983-1985
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
Parker-Gray Historic District Papers, 1983-1985
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
268
1 box (0.5 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Peter Farnham, 1992.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Parker-Gray Historic District is a locally designated historic district in Alexandria, Virginia and an adjunct to the Old and Historic District. The Old and Historic District was established in 1946; a proposed expansion of that district to include the historically African-American Parker-Gray area in 1974 was unsuccessful. In 1977-1978 the expansion and National Register listing were again proposed, and met with opposition from the African-American community.
As of 2008, the Uptown/Parker-Gray Historic District was approved as a Virginia Landmarks Register resource and in the process of being nominated to the National Register of Historic Places.
Scope and Content
This collection contains papers dating from May 1983 to July 1985 and relating to the process of evaluating the Parker-Gray Historic District under the City of Alexandria's historic preservation ordinance. Included are dockets and minutes from Planning Commission and City Council meetings and hearings, correspondence, petitions, news clippings, and meeting agendas/minutes from the Northwest Old Town Civic Association.
Arrangement
Chronological order.
Index Terms
African American neighborhoods--Virginia--Alexandria; Historic districts--Virginia--Alexandria
Contents List
- Correspondence and reports, 1983 (Box-folder 268:1)
- Planning Commission Hearing, docket and testimony, February 1984 (Box-folder 268:2)
- City Council Hearing, docket and minutes, March 1984 (Box-folder 268:3)
- Correspondence and reports, March-April 1984 (Box-folder 268:4)
- City Council Meetings, dockets and minutes, April-May 1984 (Box-folder 268:5)
- Correspondence and reports, May 1984 (Box-folder 268:6)
- Correspondence and reports, June 1984 (Box-folder 268:7)
- Petition and work sheets (1), June 1984 (Box-folder 268:8)
- Petition and work sheets (2), June 1984 (Box-folder 268:9)
- City Council Hearing/Meeting, dockets and testimony, June 1984 (Box-folder 268:10)
- Correspondence and reports, July-August 1984 (Box-folder 268:11)
- Planning Commission, docket, September 1984 (Box-folder 268:12)
- Correspondence and reports, September-October 1984 (Box-folder 268:13)
- Planning Commission/City Council, dockets, October 1984 (Box-folder 268:14)
- Correspondence and reports, March-April 1985 (Box-folder 268:15)
- Planning Commission, dockets, March-April 1985 (Box-folder 268:16)
- Correspondence and reports, August-September 1985 (Box-folder 268:17)
- Planning Commission/City Council, dockets, September-October 1985 (Box-folder 268:18)
- News clippings, January 1984-July 1985 (Box-folder 268:19)
- Northwest Old Town Civic Association, meeting agendas and minutes (Box-folder 268:20)